Guide to the Jackson J. Benson Research material about Wallace Stegner, ca. 1909-1992
Department of Special Collections
Jackson J. Benson Research material about Wallace Stegner,
ca. 1909-1992
Special Collections M0952
Benson, Jackson J.
13.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Research card files (4 boxes) labeled "chronology" and "topic" may not be read or copied until 2005. Back-up tapes may be listened to and transcripts read, but no copies of the interviews (recorded or transcripts) are to be made until 2005. We will duplicate original tapes that currently have no back-up copy at cost so a reader may listen to them, but there may be a short delay. Original letters represented in the collection in photocopy form cannot be photocopied by Stanford. Letters selected from Stegner's office are held by the University of Utah. Originals of other letters are held by private individuals.
Provenance
Gift of Jackson Benson, 1997.
Biography
American biographer of Hemingway, Steinbeck and most recently, author of the biography WALLACE STEGNER: HIS LIFE AND WORK. New York: Viking, 1996.
Scope and Content
128 interview cassette tapes of Stegner and his associates, transcripts of the interviews, 100 back-up tapes; annotated copies of correspondence including that with Phil and Peg Gray; copies of Stegner periodical fiction, essays, and articles, including all of the very early material; copies of reviews of Stegner's major works and story collections; clippings; and Benson's card files of sorted research notes.
Access Terms
Gray, Peg.; Gray, Phil.; Stegner, Wallace Earle, 1909-; American literature--20th century.; Phonotapes.; Wallace Stegner: his life and work.
Container List
- Original Accession
  - Interviews, 124 original tapes (Box 1-4)
    restricted; may be listened to but not duplicated until 2005
  - Interviews, 98 copies of tapes (Box 5-7)
  - Reviews of Stegner's works (Box 8-9)
  - Interview transcripts with Stegner & family - (Box 10-11)
    restricted; may be read but not duplicated until 2005
  - Clippings (Box 11-12)
  - Interviews with others (Box 13-15)
    - restricted; may be read but not duplicated until 2005
  - Letters to Stegner (Box 16)
  - Letters to Phil & Peg Gray, 1939-1979; letters to Stegner from special correspondents (Box 17)
  - "Fame files," 1960-1964; manuscript materials, drafts, working notes; Stegner periodical fiction, 1934-1971; published Stegner essays & articles, 1935-1947 (Box 18)
  - Published Stegner essays and articles, 1947-1967 (Box 19)
  - Published Stegner essays and articles, 1969-1992 (Box 20)
  - Card file notes; early childhood to 1934 (Box 21)
    - restricted; may not be viewed or duplicated until 2005
  - Card file notes; 1935-1954 (Box 22)
    restricted; may not be viewed or duplicated until 2005
  - Card file notes; 1955-1990 (Box 23)
  - Card file notes; topics Age to Writing (Box 24)
- Addendum:, Accession 1998-006
  - 1. Uncollected Stegner stories, mostly very early (Box 25)
  - 2. Additional reviews of short story collections (Box 25)
  - 3. 4 cassette tapes (2 are copies): (Box 25)
    - a. Interview with Wallace Stegner, 1987. Amer. Audio Prose Library
    - b. Wallace Stegner reading "The Spectator Bird" and "Crossing to Safety," (excerpts), 1987. Amer. Audio Prose Library
    - 4. 2 cassette tapes: Wallace Stegner reads "Beyond the Glass Mountain," and other works from collected stories, 1990